# **Evan Velasco**

1350 E St SE Apt #394, Washington, DC 20003 - (805) 657-5838 - evan.velasco@live.com

## **Summary**

Analytics professional with 4 years of experience in advertising technology and monetization, specializing in extracting business insights from massive datasets. Experience with ad-hoc analysis, ETL, data warehousing, dashboarding, A/B testing, forecasting, and data driven product development. Possesses strong knowledge of SQL, Excel, Tableau, Domo, Python and R.

## **Professional Experience**

#### **Senior Business & Sales Strategic Analyst**

The Washington Post, Washington, DC, February 2023-Present

- Technical data lead for Pricing team, focused on improving forecasting models, customer segmentation, and building new data products.
- Built "Revenue at Risk" dashboard which utilizes Google Ad Manager's forecasting API to estimate ad under-delivery.

#### **Senior Business Intelligence Analyst**

The Washington Post, Washington, DC, April 2022-January 2023

- Business Intelligence lead for Zeus Technology, an in-house advertising technology company which builds a variety of products including a header bidding wrapper and a self-serve ad buying platform.
- Built forecasting models (regression, financial, and product focused) in Excel and R to predict impact of future changes and led analysis measuring the effects of these changes.
- Built new data products such as automated alerting for engineering errors, ad speed reporting, contextual tagging model reporting, and granular reporting based on log level data.
- Worked with engineers to build a data backend using Redshift, AWS Athena/S3, and Google BigQuery.

#### **Business Intelligence Analyst**

The Washington Post, Washington, DC, April 2021-April 2022

- Managed analytics for programmatic ad product, providing data and analysis to the sales, finance, product, consumer success, and engineering teams.
- Represented advertising team in A/B tests, measuring impact of new technologies and site layout changes.
- Built time series models in R to estimate future programmatic CPMs and used decomposition methods to analyze trends in the programmatic marketplace.
- Automated programmatic reporting using Excel, Python and Domo, reducing time spent on financial and operational reporting by 30 hours per week and unlocking additional metrics for new insights.

#### **Revenue Analyst**

Hive Media Group, Carlsbad, CA, August 2019-April 2021

- Analyzed and optimized various channels of programmatic ad revenue including display, native, and video across 20+ sites with over 5 billion ad impressions served monthly.
- Managed analytics and A/B testing for M&A team, completing 3 successful web acquisitions and increased revenue by +50% YoY post acquisition.
- Built statistical model which used expected value to find optimal article length, informing new content strategies.
- Built reporting dashboards in Tableau to analyze ad metrics that led to actionable strategic initiatives.

## **Education**

#### **University of California San Diego**

Class of 2019

B.S. Joint Mathematics-Economics, Business Minor

## **Skills**

- Excel: Lookups, Pivot Tables, Modeling, VBA
- **Programming:** Python, R, Advanced SQL
- BI: Tableau, Looker, Domo, Google Analytics, Redshift, AWS S3, Snowflake, MySQL, BigQuery
- **SQL:** Joins, CTEs, Window Functions, Arrays
- Statistics / Machine Learning: A/B Testing, Time Series Forecasting, Regression, K-Nearest Neighbors, Decision Trees/Random Forest